Register to The Isidor Achron Papers
Yale University Music Library
The Isidor Achron Papers
1922-1989
MSS 68
Yale University Music Library
1.5
(4 boxes)
Music, correspondence, photographs, and additional materials by and about the composer and pianist Isidor Achron (1892-1948).
Achron, Isidor, 1892-1948
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to researchers by appointment. There are no restricted materials in the collection. Please contact the Special Collections staff to schedule an appointment. Some of the materials may be stored at the Library's off-campus shelving facility, so researchers should allow at least two business days to have the appropriate boxes paged.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Isidor Achron Papers were established in the Music Library of Yale University by Mrs. Lois Chazen in 1992.
Arrangement
In 10 series as follows: I. Music. II. Correspondence of I. Achron and L. Karina. III. Photographs. IV. Programs and Clippings. V. Legal Documents. VI. Publicity and Biographical Material. VII. Miscellaneous. VIII. Additional Materials Relating to Jascha Heifetz. IX. Additional Materials Relating to Hildegarde. X. Sound Recordings
Scope and Contents
The Isidor Achron Papers document the careers of Achron and his wife, singer Lea Karina. The Papers hold sketches, manuscript music, and printed editions of Achron's musical compositions, as well as songs which other composers wrote specifically for Karina. The Papers also include correspondence, photographs, programs, clippings, biographical materials, and miscellaneous materials relating to both Jascha Heifetz and Achron's pupil, popular singer Hildegarde.
Biographical / Historical
Born November 24, 1892, in Warsaw, Achron received his early musical training from his father. He later attended the St. Petersburg Conservatory where he studied piano with Annette Essipoff and Nicolai Doubsassoff, composition with Anatol Liadoff, and orchestration with Max Steinberg. He received his artist's diploma in 1915 and embarked on his first concert tour of Russia. Further plans for performing were interrupted by World War I, however, with Achron being called to serve three years in the Russian army.
In 1922 Achron emigrated to the United States, becoming a citizen in 1928. Achron's life changed on March 21, 1923 when he received an urgent telegram from Jascha Heifetz that read, "I am offering you a position as accompanist for tour beginning May 1, 1923 terminating May 1, 1924 including tour of the orient." For the next ten years Achron served as Heifetz's principal accompanist, recording an extensive discography and performing chamber and solo recitals in major music centers all over the world.
On June 14, 1935 Achron married the mezzo-soprano Lea Karina. Karina, born in Helsinki in 1914, made her singing debut with the Helsingfors Symphony Orchestra in 1931 under the baton of Jean Sibelius. She was an accomplished pianist as well as singer who was able to perform vocal repertoire in nine different languages. In 1941 she made her New York debut at Town Hall with her husband accompanying. She went on to have a successful career in radio and later served as audio director for the popular television show Your Hit Parade. Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco and Nicolas Slonimsky were among the composers who dedicated songs to her.
The mid 1930s witnessed Achron's return to solo performance as well as serious work as a composer. In 1937 he completed his First Concerto for Piano and Orchestra which he premiered on December 9, 1937 at Carnegie Hall with the New York Philharmonic, John Barbirolli conducting. He later performed the concerto with the London Symphony Orchestra and the Colonne Orchestra of Paris. Major publishers began to show interest in Achron's compositions with the publication of the First Piano Concerto and the first Sonnet for violin and piano in 1939 both by Carl Fischer, Inc. In 1937, Achron's song "Do You Know That The Moon Can Talk" was published by Chappell & Co., Ltd. under the pseudonym of Julian Dorr while the Suite Grotesque for piano was published in 1943 by G. Schirmer. Among those to whom Achron dedicated compositions were Heifetz, Yehudi Menuhin, Gregor Piatigorsky, and Mischa Elman. In 1946 Achron gave his final Carnegie Hall recital performing his own solo works as well as pieces by Mozart, Ravel, Liszt, and Chopin. He died suddenly on May 12, 1948 in New York City. Lea Karina remained in New York City teaching voice lessons and continuing her work in radio. She died on December 22, 1988. The lives and careers of both Achron and Karina are documented in the Papers with manuscript and published music, correspondence, programs, reviews, photographs, and miscellaneous materials.
The Isidor Achron Papers also contain additional material of Jascha Heifetz and Lea Karina's student Hildegarde Loretta Sell, the popular ballroom singer and radio personality of the 1930s and 40s. The Heifetz material consists of magazine articles, newspaper clippings, concert programs, and a caricature of Heifetz and Achron. The Hildegarde material consists of music, correspondence, photographs, newspaper clippings, programs, and publicity material.
Composers -- United States; Pianists -- United States; Singers -- Correspondence; Hildegarde, 1906-2005; Achron, Isidor, 1892-1948; Barbirolli, John, 1899-1970; Castelnuovo-Tedesco, Mario, 1895-1968; Deis, Carl, 1883-1960; Heifetz, Jascha, 1901-1987; Judson, Arthur, 1881-1975; Karina, Lia, 1914-1988; Klematti, Heikki, 1876-1953; Koussevitzky, Serge, 1874-1951; Menuhin, Yehudi, 1916-1999; Slonimsky, Nicolas, 1894-1995; Steinway, Theodore E., 1883-1957; Stokowski, Leopold, 1882-1977; Swanson, Gloria, 1897-1983; Volpe, Arnold, 1869-1940
- Music, Series I
  - Music Composed by Isidor Achron
    - [American fantasie] American fantasie / music by L. Karin., 6 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      General
      Holograph, photocopy.
      Annotations in pencil and pen.
      On cover: L. Karin [crossed out, replaced with I.A.]
      For piano.
      2 copies.
    - [Balerina-valse] Balerina-valse., 5 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - [Concertos, piano, orchestra, no. 1, op. 2] Concerto pour piano et orchestre / par Isidor Achron., [1937?]; 1 manuscript score (103 p.); 43 cm.
      Manuscript (photocopy)
      Cataloged separately as Misc. Ms. 382.
    - [Concertos, piano, orchestra, no. 1, op. 2, arr.] Concerto no. 1 for piano / Isidor Achron. -- New York: C. Fischer, 1939., 1 score (41 p.); 31 cm. (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Plate no.: 28403-40
      Arr. for 2 pianos.
      On cover: To dear Jane: I dare you to tackle this! composed by my teacher. Love, Hildegarde, April 15, 1947.
      Annotations in pen and pencil [1 copy only]
    - [Concertos, piano, orchestra, no. 2, op. 3, A major] Second concerto in A major for piano and orchestra, op. 3. / by Isidor Achron., [1942?]; 1 manuscript score (116 p.); 43 cm.
      Cataloged separately as Misc. Ms. 381.
    - [Concertos, piano, orchestra, no. 2, op. 3] Second concerto for piano and orchestra, op. 3., 28 parts; 34 cm. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Copyist's manuscript on transparencies.
      Orchestral parts.
    - [Concertos, piano, orchestra, no. 2, op. 3] Second concerto for piano and orchestra, op. 3., 28 parts; 33 cm. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - [Concertos, piano, orchestra, no. 2, op. 3] Second concerto for piano and orchestra, op. 3., 28 parts; 33 cm. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - [Concertos, piano, orchestra, no. 2, op. 3, arr.] Second concerto for piano and orchestra in A major, op. 3 [1938], 1 score (64 p.); 32 cm. (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Holograph in pencil.
      Arr. for two pianos.
      At end: III-Sep. 12th-1938
      Sep. 30th-1938
      N.Y.
      started-June 22nd-1938
      finished Sep. 30th-1938
    - [Concertos, piano, orchestra, no. 2, op. 3, arr.] Second concerto for piano and orchestra, op. 3., 1 score (62 p.); 32 cm. (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Copyist's manuscript on transparency.
      At end: June 22nd-1938.
      August 16th-1939. New York
    - [Do you know that the moon can talk?] Do you know that the moon can talk? / Julian Dorr. -- London: Chappell, 1937., 1 score (2 p.); 31 cm. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      For voice and piano.
      On cover: I know you will do it beautifully, love, Lea [1 copy only]
      Julian Dorr was a pseudonym for Isidor Achron.
    - [Gavotte-satirique, op. 10] Gavotte-satirique for cello and piano, op. 10., 1 score (4 p.) + 1 part (2 p.); 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Inside cover: To Gregor Piatigorsky.
    - [Gavotte-satirique, op. 10, arr.] Gavotte-satirique for piano, op. 10., 2 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - [Gavotte satirique, op. 10, arr.] Gavotte satirique, op. 10 / Isidor Achron. -- New York: C. Fischer, 1943., 5 p. of music; 31 cm. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Plate no.: 29517-3
    - [Gavotte-satirique, op. 10, arr.] Gavotte-satirique for violin and piano, op. 10., 1 part (2 p.); 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Violin part only.
    - [Happy birthday FDR] Happy birthday FDR / music by Isidor Achron; words by Friede Rothe., 1 score (4 p.); 32 cm. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - [Happy birthday FDR] Happy birthday FDR / music by Isidor Achron; words by Friede Rothe., 1 score (3 p.); 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 9)
      2 copies, 1 is negative photostat.
    - [Improvisation, violin, piano, op. 11] Improvisation, violin with piano accompaniment, op. 11 / Isidor Achron. -- New York: C. Fischer, 1946., 1 score (5 p.) + 1 part (2 p.); 31 cm. (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Plate no.: N 1090
    - [Improvisation, violin, piano, op. 12] Improvisation for violin and piano, op. 12., 1 score (5 p.) + 1 part (2 p.); 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - [Improvisation, violin, piano, op. 12, arr.] Improvisation, op. 12., 1 score (5 p.); 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Inside cover: To Lucie Bigelow Rosen.
      Arr. for theremin and piano.
    - [Nocturne-fantasia, op. 9] Nocturne-fantasia for violin and piano, op. 9., 1 score (5 p.) + 1 part (2 p.); 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - [Nocturne-fantasia, op. 9, arr.] Nocturne-fantasia for cello and piano, op. 9., 1 score (5 p.) + 1 part (2 p.); 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 11)
      2 copies, 1 with annotations in pencil.
    - [Nocturne fantasia, op. 9, arr.] Nocturne fantasia / Isidor Achron. -- New York: C. Fischer, 1943., 7 p. of music; 31 cm. (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Plate no.: 29565-5
      Arr. for piano.
      Annotations in pencil, 1 copy.
    - [Sonata, piano, op. 14] Sonata for piano, op. 14., 22 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 12)
      At end: May 16th-1947 New York.
    - [Sonnets, violin, piano, no. 1, op. 5] Sonnet / Isidor Achron. -- New York: C. Fischer, 1940., 1 score (5 p.) + 1 part (2 p.); 31 cm. (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Plate no.: 28911-6
      Inside cover: To Yehudi Menuhin.
    - [Sonnets, violin, piano, no. 1, op. 5] Sonnet no. 1 for violin and piano, op. 5., 1 score (4 p.) + 1 part (1 p.); 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - [Sonnets, violin, piano, no. 1, op. 5, arr.] Sonnet / Isidor Achron. -- New York: C. Fischer, 1939., 5 p. of music; 31 cm. (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Plate no.: 28808-4
      Inside cover: To Rose Morley.
    - [Sonnets, violin, piano, no. 2, op. 6] Sonnet no. 2 for violin and piano, op. 6., 1 score (6 p.); 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Annotations in pencil.
      Inside cover: To Jascha Heifetz.
    - [Sonnets, violin, piano, no. 2, op. 6] Sonnet no. 2 / Isidor Achron. -- New York: C. Fischer, 1942., 1 score (7 p.) + 1 part (2 p.); 31 cm. (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Plate no.: 29311-8
    - [Sonnets, violin, piano, no. 2, op. 6, arr.] Sonnet, no. 2, op. 6 / Isidor Achron. -- New York: C. Fischer, 1942., 5 p. of music; 31 cm. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - [Sonnets, violin, piano, no. 2, op. 6, arr.] Sonnet no. 2 for piano, op. 6., 4 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Annotations in pen and pencil.
      At end: Feb-16th-1940 N.Y.
      3 copies.
    - [Sonnets, violin, piano, no. 2, op. 6, arr.] Sonnet no. 2 for piano, op. 6., 1 p. of music [p. 3]; 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Incomplete, lacks 4 p.
      Annotations in pen and red pencil.
    - [Sonnets, piano, no. 3, op. 13] Sonnet no. 3 / Isidor Achron. -- New York: G. Schirmer, 1949., 8 p. of music; 31 cm. (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Plate no.: 41748c
    - [Sonnets, piano, no. 3 op. 13] Sonnet no. 3. -- [1948], 9 p. of music; 33 cm. (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Proof copy.
      Annotations in red pencil.
    - [Suite grotesque, op. 7] Suite grotesque: for the piano: op. 7 / by Isidor Achron., [1941?]; 1 manuscript score (66 p.); 43 cm
      Contents: Gavotte -- Minuet -- Tango -- Polka -- Valse.
      Cataloged separately as Misc. Ms. 380.
    - [Suite grotesque, op. 7] Suite grotesque for the piano / Isidor Achron. -- New York: G. Schirmer, 1943., 5 v. of music; 31 cm. (Box 2, Folder 14)
      Contents: Gavotte - Minuet - Tango - Polka - Valse.
    - [Suite grotesque, op. 7. Gavotte] Gavotte-grotesque for piano, op. 7., 3 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - [Suite grotesque, op. 7. Minuet] Minuet-grotesque for piano, op. 7., 3 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 14)
      At end: March-3-1940 N.Y.
    - [Suite grotesque, op. 7. Polka] Polka-grotesque for piano, op. 7., 4 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - [Suite grotesque, op. 7. Tango] Tango-grotesque for piano, op. 7., 2 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - [Suite grotesque, op. 7. Valse] Valse-grotesque for piano, op. 7., 4 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - [Suite grotesque, op. 7, arr.] Suite-grotesque, op. 7., 5 parts; 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 14)
      String parts to accompany piano version.
    - [They came to tell me your faults] Faults / music by Isidor Achron; words by Sarah Teasdale., 1 score (3 p.); 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - [They came to tell me your faults] Faults / music by Isidor Achron; words by Sarah Teasdale., 1 score (2 p.); 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - [Valse de concert, op. 11] Valse de concert for piano, op. 11., 7 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - [Valse dramatique, op. 4] Valse dramatique for violin and piano, op. 4., 1 score (4 p.); 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 15)
      Inside cover: To Mischa Elman.
    - [Valse dramatique, op. 4] Valse dramatique, violin with piano accompaniment / Isidor Achron. -- New York: C. Fischer, 1941., 1 score (5 p.) + 1 part (2 p.); 31 cm. (Box 2, Folder 15)
      Plate no.: 29110-6
    - [Valse dramatique, op. 4, arr.] Valse dramatique / Isidor Achron. -- New York: C. Fischer, 1939., 5 p. of music; 31 cm. (Box 2, Folder 15)
      Plate no.: 28807-4
    - [Valse fantastique, op. 8] Valse fantastique for violin and piano, op. 8., 1 score ( 3 p.) + 1 part (1 p.); 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 15)
      2 copies, 1 lacks part.
    - [Valse intime] Valse intime for piano solo / Isidor Achron. -- New York: C. Fischer, 1934., 2 p. of music; 31 cm. (Box 2, Folder 15)
      Plate no.: 26922-2
  - Music Arranged by Isidor Achron
    - [A kolo] A kolo, a Croatian folk-dance., 1 score (2 p.); 39 cm. (Box 2, Folder 16)
      English translation by Jeanne Casselle.
    - [Come laddie] Come laddie, a Slovak folksong., 1 score (1 p.); 26 cm. (Box 2, Folder 16)
      Holograph with typescript lyrics, photocopy.
    - [Cossack's farewell] A cossack's farewell (oy kriatshe, kriatshe), (a Ukrainian folksong), 1 score (1 p.); 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - [Czech folksongs] Anonymous Czech folksongs from the collection of Dr. Oscar W. Junek., 30 items with 3 letters to Junek and others. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - [Czech folksongs] Arrangements of 6 Czech folksongs from Dr. Oscar W. Junek., 1 score (12 p.); 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 17)
      Holograph.
    - [Czech folksongs] Sketches of Czech folksongs., 6 p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 17)
      Manuscript.
      Vocal line only.
    - [Great lord is a peasant] A great lord is a peasant, a Czech folksong., 1 score (1 p.); 31 cm. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - [Kdybys byl jenicku] Kdbys byl jenicku., 1 score (1 p.); 30 cm. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - [I love to love] I love to love (sil jsem proso), (a Czech folk-song), 1 score (1 p.); 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 18)
      English version by Jeanne Casselle.
    - [My golden mother] My golden mother (a Czech folk song), 1 score (1 p.); 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - [Sad times have come] Sad times have come, a Slovak folksong., 1 score (1 p.); 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - [Under our window] Under our window, a Slovak folksong., 1 score (1 p.); 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - [Why didn't you come?] Why don't you come?, (a Slovak folk-song), 1 score (1 p.); 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Music by Other Composers
    - [Gedichte, op. 25. Abendlied] Drei Gedichte für ein Singstimme u. Klavier, op. 25, no. 3 / Joseph Achron. -- Moscow: Russicher Musik Verlag, 1912., Achron, Joseph; 1 score (5 p.); 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 19)
      Contents: Abendlied.
      Russian and German words.
      Plate no.: R.M.V. 183
      Text by Karl Ernst Knodt.
    - [Songs, op. 52. Licht so traumend] Canzonetta, Licht so traumend, op. 52, no. 2., Achron, Joseph; 1 score (3 p.); 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 19)
      Holograph[?] in ink.
    - [Damajanti] Damajanti., Arensky, Anton; 1 score (7 p.); 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 20)
      Manuscript in ink.
      Russian words.
      Annotations in pencil and ink.
    - [Pustinya] The desert., Balakirev, Miliĭ Alekseevich, 1837-1910; 1 score (4 p.); 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 20)
      Russian and English words.
      Annotations on pencil.
    - [Nachtigall hat ausgesungen] Die Nachtigall hat ausgesungen., Bolderman, Luci; 1 score (2 p.); 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 20)
      German and English words.
      Text by H. Michaud.
    - [Hear but the wind...] Hear but the wind..., Bucky-Sarsen, Frida; 1 score (2 p.); 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - [Hear the wind whispering] Hear the wind whispering., Bucky-Sarsen, Frida; 1 score (3 p.); 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 20)
      Annotations in ink.
    - [Hear the wind whispering] Hear the wind whispering / Frida Bucky-Sarsen. -- New York: Boosey and Hawkes, 1944., Bucky-Sarsen, Frida; 1 score (5 p.); 31 cm. (Box 2, Folder 20)
      Plate no.: 2443-3
    - [Moonlight Everywhere] Moonlight everywhere., Bucky-Sarsen, Frida; 1 score (2 p.); 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - [Pansies] Pansies: 2 poems by D.H. Lawrence for a voice and piano., Castelnuovo-Tedesco, Mario, 1895-1968; 1 score (9 p.); 33 cm. (Box 2, Folder 21)
      Contents: 1. When I went to the film. -- 2. What is man without an income?
      1 score (10 p.); 34 cm.
      Holograph in ink.
      On cover: for Lia Karina with true friendship, Mario.
      At end of no. 1: Mario, Larchmont. 26 Sett: 1939.
      At end of no. 2: Mario, Larchmont (N.Y.)-21 Sett; 1939.
    - [Pansies] When I went to the film; What is man without an income?, Castelnuovo-Tedesco, Mario, 1895-1968; 1 score (9 p.); 33 cm. (Box 2, Folder 21)
      At end of no. 1: Mario, Larchmont(N.Y.) 26 Sett: 1939.
      At end of no. 2: Mario, Larchmont. 21 Sett. 1939.
    - [Romances viejos] Romances viejos para canto y piano / Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco. -- Ricordi: Milan, 1935., Castelnuovo-Tedesco, Mario, 1895-1968; 1 score (8 p.); 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 21)
      Plate no.: 123638
      Inside cover: To Lia Carina [sic] after a charming evening in her house and an "exhibition" of my songs. Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco New York-Sept 19th 1939
    - [When I have sung my songs] When I have sung my songs, song for voice., Charles, Ernest; 1 score (2 p.); 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 21)
      Incomplete copy.
      On cover: Lea Karina Achron, 1939-New York City
    - [D'une prison] D'une prison., Daudet, Léon, 1867-1942; 1 score (3 p.); 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 22)
      French words.
      Inside cover: Renaldo Hahn
    - [Departure] The departure / Mischa Elman. --New York: G. Schirmer, 1917., Elman, Mischa, 1891-1967; 1 score (1 p.); 31 cm. (Box 2, Folder 22)
      Plate no. 27516c.
      Text by Alfred Tennyson.
      Inside cover: To my sister, Minna
      Incomplete, 1 p. only.
    - [In stillen Gärten] In stillen Gärten / Mischa Elman. -- New York: G. Schirmer, 1917., Elman, Mischa, 1891-1967; 1 score (6 p.); 30 cm. (Box 2, Folder 22)
      Plate no.: 27582c
      Text by Nathan Sulzberger, translated by T. Baker.
      FOR VOICE AND PIANO.
      Inside cover: To Mme. Alda
    - [Bruder Staubingerd. Küssen ist keine Sünd] Küssen ist keine Sünd, Lied aus der Operette: Bruder Staubinger., Eysler, Edm.; 1 score (4 p.); 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 22)
      German words.
    - [Yugu mou gpyz] Yugu mou gpyz., Fomin, Ieoris; 1 score (2 p.); 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - [Berceuse, piano] Berceuse, le pays de rêves., Fraser-Henry, Florence; 3 p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 23)
      Manuscript "List of Movements" attached.
    - [Chaconne, piano] Chaconne., Fraser-Henry, Florence; 2 p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - [Drake's drum] Drake's drum., Fraser-Henry, Florence; 1 p. of music. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - [Fandango, piano] Fandango., Fraser-Henry, Florence; 3 p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - [Galliard, piano] Galliard (old northern type), Fraser-Henry, Florence; 2 p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - [Hornpipe, piano] Hornpipe., Fraser-Henry, Florence; 1 p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - [Minuet, piano] Minuet., Fraser-Henry, Florence; 2 p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - [Pavane, piano] Pavane., Fraser-Henry, Florence; 2 p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - [Pink bonnet, Irish jig] Pink bonnet, Irish jig "Sligo Fair.", Fraser-Henry, Florence; 3 p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - [Quick Coronto] Quick Coronto., Fraser-Henry, Florence; 2 p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - [Rainbow] The rainbow., Fraser-Henry, Florence; 1 p. of music; 15 cm. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - [Sarabande, piano] "Sarabande.", Fraser-Henry, Florence; 2 p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - [Siciliano, piano] Siciliano., Fraser-Henry, Florence; 2 p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - [Sweetbriar] "Sweetbriar," country dance., Fraser-Henry, Florence; 1 p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 23)
      At end: P.T.O.
    - [Tordion] Tordion., Fraser-Henry, Florence; 1 p. of music; 24 cm. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - [American preludes] Twelve american preludes / Alberto Ginastera. -- New York: Fischer, 1949., Ginastera, Alberto, 1916-1983; 13 p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 24)
      Plate no.: 30045-6
      Proof sheets.
    - [Romansy, op. 28. Zhit'! Budem zhit'!] Lesst, lesst euch aus, op. 28 no. 5., Gliere, Reinhold; 1 score (3 p.); 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - [Nancy's reply] Nancy's reply., Hogan, Frank; 1 score (8 p.); 30 cm. (Box 2, Folder 24)
      Letter to Lea Karina attached.
    - [Ila twej mitosei] Ila twej mitosei., Karazinski, Z.; 1 conductor's score (1 p.) + 15 parts; 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 24)
      For chamber ensemble.
    - [Le roi de Lahore] Le roi de Lahore: Ferme les yeux, o belle maîtresse, romance-sérénade., Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912; 1 score (6 p.); 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 25)
      Copyist's manuscript.
    - [Kozyoi] Der Ziegenbock., Mussorgsky, Modest Petrovich, 1839-1881; 1 score (4 p.); 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - [Songs by Franz Werfel] Three songs by Franz Werfel., Newlin, Dika; 1 score (10 p.); 34 cm. (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - [April] April, song for high voice., Slonimsky, Nicolas, 1894-1995; 1 score (3 p.); 31 cm. (Box 2, Folder 26)
      Text by Theodosia Garrison.
      At end: March 26, 1928.
    - [Bailecito] Bailecito -- [1947], Souviron, Yvette; 1 score (3 p.); 33 cm. (Box 2, Folder 26)
      Spanish words.
    - [Deepest regret] Deepest regret., Souviron, Yvette; 1 score (2 p.); 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - [Gaucho mensajero] Gaucho menasajero (malambo argentino)., Souviron, Yvette; 1 score (3 p.); 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 26)
      English translation attached.
      At end: Yvette Souviron, Habana 1960